We will see a
true flourishing
of entrepreneurship.  I'm
sure it's
close.  I think it
will really start in the
next year or two.
This is Greg,
co-founder of OpenAI, the
company
behind ChatGPT, which
is used by over a
billion people every week.
I'm pretty good at
writing code.  But I
don't write
software anymore.  I control
the AI ​​to write code,
giving it lots of
feedback and
guidance.
When people create
products, how do they
strategically
design something that won't
become obsolete
due to new models?  I'll
show you what I
experienced recently.
Am I
ambitious enough about
AI?
I think the answer to the
question of whether we are
ambitious enough will always
be "no," because we
can always
do more.
Where should someone start this
weekend who
wants to take their
agent work to the next
level with just an
hour to spare?
I would say, first of
all,
this video is
sponsored by HubSpot.
I wanted to talk
about purely practical
things.  I was recently
talking to a
Nobel
laureate in
economics, and the
theme that kept coming up was that
we have powerful
AI models but lack
applications.
Do you think what
you're
launching this
year will help change that and
show people the
true power of AI?    It is
very interesting
to observe, first of
all, how many
people use
ChatGPT.  We have 1.2
billion
weekly active users
.  About 300 million
people use chat every week
for
health queries, right?
To help yourself in your
personal life.
At the same time, many of these
use cases are only
superficial.  We see
from the metrics: if
a person uses
the chat for three different
tasks—three things it
can help with—they
become an active
user.  You
stay with us,
continue to
use chat,
and want to
use it
more.  But reaching
these three
use cases is not an
easy task.
Mhm.
In some ways, it's even
logical, because there's an AI that
can do everything, but
what exactly can it
do for you?  It's like
sometimes someone
What is this magical thing,
huh?
That's right!  So it's important
to really find the
magic that
resonates with
you.  But at the same time, I
think it shows a
huge opportunity
, a huge space,
almost a gap, where
you communicate with AI, and
AI knows what it's
capable of, and could
offer you, "
Hey, you asked me to
do this for you."
Actually, I could
do even
more, right?
For example, here's an idea.  I
can make a whole
presentation, a
spreadsheet.  "
So, we've really
explored this, but
I feel like there's
something here that ties into what
you want
from AI—which is simplicity.
Truth?  You don't
need an interface
with buttons,
sliders, and
model selection,
nothing like that.  This is not the
AI ​​we were
promised.  You want
something you can
talk to, that can
solve problems,
help,
help you achieve
goals, but that can
even be
proactive.  It
might say to you, "
Hey, you have
this email in your inbox from the person
you've been ignoring for
the past few days,
and I actually did some
research and it
turns out that this is the
correct answer
to the question, and I've
prepared a draft
."  Do you approve? "And by
the way, that
use case I
just mentioned is not
theoretical.  With
thoughts, I actually
got exactly this
example that happened
to me right before
we started this
podcast.  And so I
think we're at a
point now where AI is
really able to be
much more
proactive and take
away a lot of the
burden of figuring out,
like, "What is
this system capable of?" and
really help
you and then
help you
achieve whatever it is that you
want to do.    Are
there any other
use cases that
were unthinkable a year
ago but are possible
now that people
should try?
Well, I think there are so
many of them, right?  There's a
whole spectrum of them, and I
think the way
I always recommend
for discovery is to
play around with the system
or see what
it's capable of.  And so
when it comes
to programming, these
models are now better at
writing
software than
practically anyone
I know.  Truth?  I'm
pretty good at writing
software.  But I
don't write
software myself anymore.  I
directed the AI ​​to
write
software.  I provide
a lot of feedback and
guidance.  So it's always
fun to set up a
little game and just
get that quick
result, just
seeing, "Okay,
how long
did it take to
implement this?"  And then
ask for something
more difficult.  I think we're at a
point now where
Astra is so proficient
in Blender and 3D
modeling.  So it's
interesting to ask her
to create 3D models
from photos and
do things like that.
You can see
her using
software like Microsoft
Paint to make a
sketch.  But you can also
ask for more
real things.
For example, I know
a friend
who wanted to
build a guest
house and used
Astra to create CAD
plans, showed them to
the contractor, and now
construction is
underway.
Ugh.
So this offers great
opportunities.  Normally
you would have to
hire someone
else.  For example, I
don't know how to create CAD
plans.  Now we
have intelligence in our pockets
that can actually
perform such
tasks for us.
Personally, I
enjoy
trying out AI in
different areas of my
life.  And I think
voice mode
makes AI very
accessible, right?  You
simply turn on
voice mode and
start talking to it
.
Voice mode is
now connected to the
tools.  So you
can ask him to
do all the same things as
in the chat.  If it's
connected to your
email and calendar,
you can ask, "
What's my schedule for
today?"  or "I
want to free up time
for reflection, how do I
do that?".  He can
view the context of
all the events on your
calendar.  I think it's
worth
stopping sometimes and
thinking: what more
ambitious thing can I
ask my AI to do
that it hasn't already done?
Let's see if
this works.
Yes, I'm just going to
show you something I
recently created.  We
live in an era where
anyone can create a
personal
productivity app, or
even several.  Here's this one
I created: I
asked to create
an app that
would prepare me for a
podcast.  I indicate
who I have an interview with,
how long it
will last, and what the
success rate is.  This is usually the
number of views
on YouTube.
Ugh.
And after that, he
sets about
creating a podcast.
He conducts
research and
suggests topics for
discussion.  That's
great, but how can I
teach him from my
experience, right?  Is there
still room for development in this
area?  Since I'm
recording this conversation,
it will come here and
check my
previous conversations.  What do
you think is
missing here and am
I ambitious enough
about AI?
I think the answer to the
question of
ambition will always
be "no," because
you can always do more.
And that's the beauty of AI
: it helps you
solve
problems and achieve what
you
want.  You know,
there are no limits to what
you can imagine, right
?  So it's just a matter of
tweaking it a little bit.  If
you were able to
achieve something, it means
you can dream a little
bigger.  So, in
my opinion, this is a super-
super cool app.
First of all, regarding
previous
research: when this
was being created, the AI ​​had already
analyzed all of
my interviews.  That's
all.  I did all the
preparatory work.
I did everything necessary.
The only thing is that it doesn't
connect to
social networks yet, but I think
it's a plugin issue.
Yes.
But yes, he
went through your
conversations.
There we have it.  And then
all the past
press releases from OpenAI.  Oh, we have a
questions tab.  I
like it.
There is a tab with questions
, a title, and a preview
—these are the questions that I
can copy.
Yes, I wonder
how much it
helps with
post-production and
creating the
final video
when it's ready?
Since this piece has
all the context about
me, about OpenAI, about the
topics you've
covered before,
how do you want to
assemble this?  I've heard of
many good
cases where Astra
helps with
video post-production
and does it
proactively.  I would be
interested if you had
an app where all you
have to do is
review the questions
and make sure you
like them.
And if not, you give
feedback and it gets
better.  You come,
conduct an interview, and the
system takes care of the rest.  How much
work do you do
now from the time of the
interview to the time of
the video being released on YouTube?
Oh, so much work.
I have a big team
, we've
documented a lot, and I've
been doing this for 12
years.  So, we have
all the files we are
referencing.
It's easier to build now with AI,
but each episode
still takes
at least 40 hours.
Oho.  And if you could
turn back that time,
right?  So that all the
technical part
is automated
and you can spend
more time
thinking about how to
make the interview
better, or how to
scale and
do much more
interviews.  So, what would you
do with that
extra time?
This question is for you: For a
small business that
uses AI in its
daily operations,
what is the role of the
business owner?  What
should they think about more?
And what is really the bottleneck
for
business right now?
I think there is something
fundamental.
First, we see so
many new small
businesses because people
feel confident
having ChatGPT, right?
Starting a business
requires so much
knowledge that it's hard,
right?  But now
you actually have a
PhD-level intellect, a
global business
consultant.  You have it
all in your pocket, and it's
free.  That's
pretty impressive,
right?  And if you're
willing to pay, you
can get even
more depth and
computing
power to
solve any
problem.  So
starting a small business is
easier than ever.
And we see this quite
specifically.  Many
small
business owners are outsourcing
so many tasks to AI that,
in addition to the ones they already
had to do, they are also
doing things
that no one would have
done before.  For example,
closing gaps in a
business strategy or
thinking about how
to create a certain
document.  Another thing is
small
business owners who
don't even realize what they
could be doing.  One
of our
employees
was telling us how he was
looking for a watch.  He
was in an
antique
watch shop and started
talking to the owner
about AI, and the owner said,
"Oh, AI, I can't
use that. I'm
just the owner of the
watch
shop."  And he said to him:
"No, no, AI can
help everyone.
Let me
show you."  "And so he
talked about some of
his problems and was like,
'Well, yeah, he does
n't actually have a
website.'"  "And so,
It's the easiest.
That's right, right? And
just like the voice of ChatGPT,
saying, 'Build me a
website.'"  Create a
great website.  "And
then the owner said,
'Hey,
every watch I have has a
story, right?'"
"And so it just
becomes really easy. You're
like, 'Okay, tell
the AI ​​the story of
each watch.'"  "And
you get this
beautiful
visualization of everything,
and you just
realize that there's this
way that
technology comes to life that's
usually almost
inaccessible to a
lot of people. And
so I think it
really pushes the point that
if you
had the best programmer in the world on
staff,
what would you have
them work on? And what
can you
do now? I
think you
mentioned somewhere that this is
really an ambition that
small
businesses should start
working on, right?
Yeah. Yeah. And I think, I think that's what
I agree with. And I think it's
really about
all of us
raising the bar of
ambition, right? We
can all achieve
more. People who
really lean into
this, I think we're
starting to see
really extraordinary
things. I'll give you
another example, by
the way, is that we have,
uh, there are these two brothers
who are blind and they're
using our
technology, and, uh,
they're using
it both in their everyday
lives and for their
work. And even for
tasks like
being able to
plug a cable into the
right port on a
computer, right?
You can
use ChatGPT
to actually provide that
information when
normally they would have to
ask someone for
help. And so I
think this kind of
empowerment, you know,
being able to help
people become more
independent, to live
their lives the way
they want to, all of that is
happening. It's
happening right
now on a massive
scale.
When someone thinks about
building something in
software, when
OpenAI is building so
much around
work and
productivity, what do
you think makes an
app
worth paying for?
There are definitely parts of
what used to be
app building
that are becoming commoditized,
becoming accessible
to everyone, becoming
massively
democratized. I
think that's a really
important thing, a
beautiful thing, right
? That there can just be
more
software. And so
the question of what the
difference is becomes even more
important. I think there's going to be
more
opportunity than
ever for
software that
creates value in
unique
ways. And partly
it's really
about having a deep
understanding of the problem.
Part of it is having a deep
understanding of your
users,
right? Think about
something like
building an
education product. There are teachers,
there are parents, there are students, right?
There are so many
stakeholders
that you have to
really think about. There are
administrators. How do you
build a product
that really provides the
right information
, has the right
safeguards, is
useful in the right
way, and who are you
selling it to? All of these
questions. So I think
those human
factors—what is the essence of
the business, what have you
discovered, what is your
idea, what is your
unique perspective on the
world—are more important than the
technical mechanics of the
implementation, like, do you
have to write in C++
or Swift? Who is interested in this?
That should never have
been a barrier.
Yeah. I've seen that
YC startups, the latest
cohorts, are 60% B2B. And my
gut tells
me that with these
tools
available to us, if
I want to be an
entrepreneur, I see
so many problems in the
consumer  sector.
Do you think we're
going to enter an era where more and
more people are going
to build
consumer businesses?
Well, I think the line
between what's
corporate and what's
consumer is going to start to
blur.
Mhm.
I think the concept of a
company is going to become less
clear in some
sense, or it's going to be
less like a
company is a bunch of
people
organized in a certain
way. I think
people are going to have
so many opportunities,
right? We're going to see this
massive renaissance
of entrepreneurship. I
think it's
coming. I think
we're just seeing the
foreshadowing of it, but
really, I think it's going
to really start in the
next
year or two. And I think
the question of whether
you're selling to
consumers or to
corporations has
certain aspects that are going to
remain the
same across the
board.
For example, when I
think about
corporate sales
, they're fundamentally
relationship-based. But if you
think of them as
relationships, the reason
you can't
do
corporate sales to
consumers is
because there are
just too
many consumers, right? It's
too big a
scale, it's too
expensive. But if you
have AI that really
amplifies your
ability to build
relationships that are really
meaningful and
really
care about
people at
scale, then
maybe the
enterprise
sales model will become
relevant even for
consumer businesses.
But the mechanics of
what a business is, I
think, will
evolve. I think
the methods of engaging with
users will
change; but the
fundamental
principles of when you
want to deliver
value and build
relationships with people
who receive that value
, and do
it as a two-way
exchange—all of those things will come
to the fore
regardless of the
industry.
Greg talks about
how much more
you can do right now,
even with a
tiny team.
If that makes you
think, "Maybe I
could start a
business like that," I want
you to think about your
first customer. You
want to listen,
understand what they
need, and do
the best you can. But
you also have notes,
follow-ups, and
spreadsheets,  that need to be
updated. Our
sponsor, HubSpot,
helps with that. Their
new intelligent CRM is a CRM
that updates itself,
keeping
customer information and your
conversations together. Its AI
notepad logs
customer calls,
drafts
follow-ups, and
suggests next
steps and updates to
customer records that
you can approve.
So you can
focus more on
the people you're
building this business for.
Check out
HubSpot's intelligent CRM
at the link in the description
, and thanks to HubSpot for
sponsoring this
episode. Now
back to Greg.
When people build
software, how do you
strategize to
build something that doesn't become
obsolete as
new models emerge?
Some
activities, I
think,
scale well as
models
get smarter, and
some are kind of a way
around the limitations of the
model. The latter is
pretty hard
to make sustainable.
And so I think there have been startups at
various points
that have really focused on that
. We
take the model, we
add some
prompts,  we have some
very carefully
designed details. And
that's not to say that
there isn't a point in time
where that's valuable. And
sometimes it's even about the
interface, right?
That at every level of
model capability, a
new
interface almost automatically emerges. In 2022,
we had AI that was
personalized enough
that it was worth reading the
answers, like GPT-4.
So it's like, of course, you
want to turn
ChatGPT into 3.5 and GPT-
4. You know, the end of
2025, I would say, is when the
era of agents for
programming really begins, when
AI goes from
20%
to 80% of software production. So you just
need a completely
different product that
takes that into account, and that's what
everyone is going to
use. Now,
I think we're starting to
enter the era of
personalized
agents. So you're going to have
cloud AI, and it's
coming in
many different form
factors. OpenAI, we
just released dots. I'm
very  I'm excited about this.
I think he has the
smartest model
that supports
this kind of technology
, and it's
incredibly useful.
It's useful to me
. I think it's going to be
useful to
a lot of people. So I
think the key
is to think about how
to scale as the
models get
smarter. And again
, part of that is
understanding the
industry. Part of that is
building relationships;
if you take a
hospital, right? There are so
many different
stakeholders, right
? It's the patient, the
doctor, the
hospital administration, the insurance
provider. There are so
many different parties.
So how do you build
trust with each of
them and create a
product that's useful to
them, and still be
able to... So, if you
think about it, if you have a
model that's getting
better, and you're already
in the industry
, your existing
customers make your product
better and more
competitive
.
Is there anything in particular that
you're looking forward to
seeing
startups
use
models to develop?
I think the
industry knowledge is also
key, because it's easy to
lose sight of  that
at OpenAI we have
technology that is
so broad,
right? It touches
every aspect of
economic
growth and
development, people's lives, both
personally and
professionally.
There's something for everyone that
can really
help, something that
can help them achieve
their goals. But
often in any
given vertical,
we're very far from
optimal, aren't
we? If you almost
think of
the economy as a
fractal, right? It's like you
zoom in and
say, "Okay, here's the
healthcare sector
." And then you
zoom in even
closer and you see a
real number of
different companies and
a lot of different
ways of doing things. And
no matter
what sector you
choose, there's so
much
opportunity that's readily available.
In fact, one of the
most interesting and
surprising things for
me about
building OpenAI was
realizing that there's
so much
inefficiency in the economy. We
could have much more
productive
processes that would
give people their
time and create
real value,
but we very rarely
connect different
industries. Right?
People just narrowly
specialize.
And now it's becoming
economically viable
to build them, because 5
years ago it would have been
just a separate
function of the company.
Now you can
build a whole
small company
around that function.
Exactly. And I think
even the classic
industries and fields
are
only there because of
the limitations of our
tools. Again
, think about how you
become an expert in
any field? You
go to school, you
specialize, and
as humanity
learns more and
more, the concept of
specialization becomes narrower and narrower
.
For example, if you're a
biologist now, you
get a PhD
in one specific
reaction, right? And it's
not connected to the
overall system.
I think when it comes
to building a
business,
the question is: can you
build much
more hybrid things?
Think about EdTech—it's an
example of how people
who are knowledgeable about
education and
technology are
combining their
knowledge to
innovate and
create new things.
I wonder if
we'll discover other fields that we've never
connected before
, but that are perfectly
complementary.  each other?
Absolutely. That's the
future of
entrepreneurship:
combining these areas
and finding the right
solutions. Can you
tell me about a
system that you
use that's
sophisticated enough
for me to
compare it to? Because sometimes
I get criticized in
the comments for
asking about
agents for the
morning briefing.
So let's not
talk about the
morning briefing.
Let's look at
something that helps
run the company,
increases
efficiency, and
makes people
say, "This is it!"
about their
productivity.
I wouldn't
underestimate the
morning
briefing agent so much, because I think it
has a lot of
depth. There's a simple
version that gives me
information that I could
just
read in my
notifications. But there's a
version that says, "Here's
a list of things that are
pending," right?
Like, "Here's a
list of Slack messages
that you haven't responded to, and
you should respond to
these people in this
order of priority." That's the
next level,
where I've already done
the research. You know,
there's a question about what
our strategy should be
in a certain
market, and I've actually
gone and even
watched all
the presentations, and these are the
things that I should look at
to
make that
decision. So that
third point—that's
where we're at now
, right? It's an
AI that can actually
do very
complex research
on a lot of different
things and give me a
condensed version of what
I should
look at. What
I'm really
excited about as the
next step,
which we haven't quite
gotten to yet, is, so to
speak, an
assistant agent,  who says, "
Hey, I actually
called these
people.  I
talked to these
colleagues of yours.  I
spoke with an
external partner
and got everything in
perfect order.
I just need
you to approve this
order and we're
ready to start
working on a new
project." AI that is
truly proactive
and capable of acting on
your behalf. That's
coming, and I
think with dots we
already have the technology for
that. So I think
we'll start to see
people start to really
use it. I
think we still have a lot of
work to do and things
to improve. But I would
say that there's a tremendous depth to
any of these use cases
, and
that's the main thing for me in
AI. If you just
look at the label "AI
that writes
software," well,
of course, we've had
AI that writes
code for 5 years now. But today's
AI that writes code is
radically
different from what it
was 5 years
ago. So I really
appreciate the depth of
application that's
possible, even though
the name on the package is the
same, and everyone's heard it
a hundred times.
When you look at
these
use cases at OpenAI,
do you have an internal
metric of how
advanced  these
models actually
affect
human productivity
?
We've also written
about this on the
blog. We've done
quite a bit of work
looking at
token usage
, looking at how
it correlates with
lines of code,
commits,
merge requests, and
things like that. And again
, all of these metrics are
just
proxy metrics. They're not
perfect, but I think
another way
to tell if
AI is really changing
productivity is
to look at what
happens when there's an
internal outage.
For example, if people
inside the company
can't
access a model,
they get really
upset, and everyone
says, "I can't
do my
job." And you're like, "
Okay, you didn't have this 6 months ago
, and now you're
saying you can't do your
job when you're
only offline for 2
hours." How is that
possible? But we
see it all the time.
It's so, so cool. And I
find that in my own
experience, in the
morning briefing with an
agent, I often
do this: as soon as
I have a question
about  OpenAI, I just
ask my agent.
I don't know why I would
do anything else, because
it's so
efficient. Often,
sometimes I even
feel a little
lazy when someone
sends me
a message with a
document. I just
try to remember
where it was? And
so it's just
connected to
everything. It can
work with mail,
Slack, or whatever you
use. And
it has all
the information, so
whenever you
need something, you just
ask it. That's
right. And it has all
the information.
Yeah. Yeah. And with
the use of
a computer, it really
goes the last mile,
allowing me
to connect to
my entire
corporate
context. And that's what
makes it so
useful because I
really have this
chief of staff. By
the way, I also have a
human chief of
staff, who is also
incredible. And I can
give her a lot more
options without
asking these
basic things that
my
AI can now answer.
Although some of these, as
you say, "basic"
questions are actually
quite complex.
For example, questions
about  different business
metrics, right? So
it has to go and
query
our data warehouse
to find, like
, growth in
some market or
customer retention curves or something
like that. I remember
at my last
job at Stripe, we
had an
analytics team that you
would send an
email to, and a
week later they would
come back with an
answer to that
query. And now I
just ask the AI, and it
does it. It's
just incredible.
Do you see areas where
people are underutilizing
tokens? Do you want to
tell people, "
Use
more tokens for this
"?
Oh, absolutely. And
look, I think there
are two dimensions here. One of
them is the era of
token maximization
, right? When people
just blindly say, "
Add more
tokens here," which is clearly not the
main goal. But
it's a good
proxy. If you're not
trying
to optimize tokens,
you're probably
going to see
performance gains that
correlate with the
increase in
tokens. And
we really see it.
We have
leaderboards. We kind of
track it.
And I think we see
that the people who are the
most proficient in
their use
are able to do
really incredible
things. Again, it
depends on the
industry, but I
love seeing,
for example, our
finance team
has gone all
AI, AI first; and
I think there are so many
things, like
workflows that used to
take a lot of time
to close out
accounts, that are now
much
faster, right? And it's
not just a feeling—
everyone is feeling this
productivity boost and
how useful it is.
We have early
adopters in our
communications team. I think
they're just able to
manage events, like
when you have a
bunch of journalists coming in, and
you're doing the
seating chart, figuring out
everyone's
food preferences, and you can
handle all of that on your
own because you have
Codex doing
most of the
work. This has been
happening since
the beginning of this year.
So we're seeing these
use cases for
AI
productivity everywhere
. And of course, there's one thing that
I think is very
easy to miss, and
it's actually
coming to everyone soon—that's the
realm of scientific
discovery, right?
We've put
massive amounts of
computing
power into
solving the
Navier-Stokes equations, this
big "
Millennium Problem," it was
about 10,000 agents
over a few
days, it's a really
massive amount of
computing, and we've
been able to create new
knowledge for humanity. And
if you think about it at a
much smaller
scale, I think
we're still
seeing a lot of
breakthroughs. So I
feel like
the people who are really
putting
the computing into the
right problem,
right? Have some
judgment and real
thinking about what's
really important, where
the computing is going to be used, and are willing to
significantly increase the
token budget—we're
really seeing this kind of
huge impact.
I think that's an important
question for a lot of people
who are just starting out with
agents and
automation:
Where do you start? What do you think about
this?  What do you think?
This blank
slate problem is the
hardest thing about AI,
how
to use it:
where to start and what
to apply? I think
my answer is always the
same: start
small. Just
try something
. Type
something, hit
enter, see what
happens, right? And I
think once you
get that
feedback, you
can
improve
the process. You can get
better. So you have to
find some
small problem in
your life, right?
Maybe it's an email in
your inbox
that you're afraid
to answer, or you
know it's going
to take a lot of
effort. And then the first
question is: how do I
get that email to the
AI, right? One
option is to copy
and paste. Another
option is to connect it
through a connector to
Gmail. I think you can
start mechanically,
putting in your own
effort, and then you
realize, "Okay, I
've done this three times, five
times, now I
understand how
this process works." Let's
automate it.
To  by the way, this is a general
principle of
software development: that's
how I've always approached
when
to build a program and
when to do it
manually—after five
iterations, it's probably time
to automate.
Yeah, I
like that. The rule of
five.
That's a pretty good
metric. Exactly.
Yeah, and I think it's
worth doing for AI, because that's how you
keep your finger on the
pulse of the problem.
Mmh.
Which I think is really
important. Ultimately,
going back to
the question of
small
business owners and AI,
the responsibility
remains with them,
right? It's still a
business that works
a certain way, the customer
either signs up or does
n't, pays or doesn't,
so they have to
care about the outcome and have a
deep understanding of the
details. The
other aspect of this
problem is how do you decide
what not to
automate? And I
wanted to ask you,
given your mission,
how do you at OpenAI decide
what not to
build next
?
I think it's really
important that people
remain in
control and in power
, right? For the goals
came from people.
The point of this technology is to
help people,
right? To help
empower everyone, to
help people
achieve more in
what they want to
do. So I think
that this "people
first" approach, this
"team of
humanity" philosophy is very
important,
fundamental to
our mission, and it's something
that really influences
our vision of things. And
so when we think
about what to build,
we always think about
how to put the
right
safeguards in place, how
to build trust, how to
ensure proper
oversight and monitoring,
and that's been a major
focus in the design of
all of our
technology, basically,
from the beginning.
Where do you start this
weekend for someone who's
ready to improve
their
agent experience and has an
hour to do it?
I would say, first of
all, sign up
for chat.openai.com. It's a
really
cool new form
factor, I think. Again,
you can talk, have a
little chat
, understand,  what it
does, but
connecting it to the
right
context
can really help with the
work, right? It
has its own cloud
computer and can
also
connect to
your local
computer. And I think
our common
understanding of how
code
agents work is this kind of
task-based system that you
micromanage and that
lives on your
laptop. You
close the laptop
and it stops
working. Obviously,
it was never the
AI ​​that we were promised, was
it? It
was never the AI ​​that we
imagined 5 years ago.
And so I think
now we have something that
really resembles the
AI ​​that we always
imagined. So,
again, start
with a small
task, like
asking it
to buy you something, or
try to... I
really
like texting
my husband,
you know? Just go
and set up a few
connectors to
feel like, "Okay, I
now have a channel to communicate
with this." And  ask
it to do some
routine task,
okay? Or give
it a
research task. And what's
really interesting is that it's
really, really
complex, isn't it?
It's powered by GPT-6
Astra, so it
actually has this
incredible brain,
the smartest and
most advanced
model of any
assistant out there,
that powers it. And that
means it
makes some
connections between things.
For example, if you
ask it
a question about what's
happening in a
certain region, it'll
understand that you're
interested in that. And then it
can proactively
let you know if there's a
new report
about that region,
maybe say, "Hey,
here's some new information."
It takes over
some of the thinking, which
I really appreciate. Do you
think this is the future of
work, or will
it be something
that we
can't even imagine now in 5 years?
Well, I think AI is always
going to be amazing. So I
think
fundamentally we're going to
have smarter
AI that's going to become more
accessible and
expand our
capabilities, but
the ways it's
used will be
unexpected
compared to what we
expect today.
So I think the form
factors
will continue
to change, and we'll
have AI that can
solve
mathematical problems
that were previously unsolvable
. So what are
people going to do with
that? What breakthroughs
will be possible
because of that? I
think about medicine and
drug development—that's
going to be incredible. Materials
science—
we're going to live in a world
where people can
solve problems
that used to
require a small
group of
experts in a specific field. You're going to be able to
do it yourself.
You're going to be able to
solve
problems that no
one has ever
thought of before, and there
will be challenges that no
one has ever
faced before, and you
can be the first to
overcome them. And I
think we're
going to do it as a
big community,
so the tools for
that... I think there's going to be a lot
more
collaboration, and these AIs
will represent you
, you're going to have AI that
works for you
. Companies are going
to have their own AI.
I think we need
to build a lot of
infrastructure, and
to do it in a reliable,
transparent way
that really
improves the lives of
humanity. I think that's the
foundation of what we
should be doing together.
That's a great answer,
and I think
we'll have a lot to
think about over the weekend, and it's not just
about agents.
Okay. I
love that.
Thank you very much, Greg. That
was incredible.
Thank you. Very grateful.